<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spencerobsitnik</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on spencerobsitnik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Softbody Phsyics Based Rodents</title>
      <link>/projects/ratformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/ratformer/</guid>
      <description>The Ultimate Ratformer    What if we could physically simulate accurate rat physics, if rats had a tendency to balloon themselves in outsized proportions and also not act like rats at all?
Those familiar with Feynman and his revolutionary work will recognize this theoretical question he posed in his seminal lectures on physics.
Today it is finally answered.
Inspired by the physics of Jelly Car, I sought to replicate this, but in 3D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall</title>
      <link>/projects/wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/wall/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Wall is a work in progress, and as such, lots of plot points/beats are omitted. Please reach out to be considered for playtesting!
This is a game about talking to a Wall. Unless it’s about something else. Hard to say, really. Wall is a short narrative adventure about friendship, loneliness, and staring at surfaces for meaning.
Features:
 A cube-shaped companion with surprisingly deep thoughts Conversations that unfold as you pace Other rooms (allegedly) At least one emotionally suspicious mannequin  It is my current project, and my intended first pubicly released project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Physics of Outerwilds</title>
      <link>/projects/outerwilds_clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/outerwilds_clone/</guid>
      <description>I love Outer Wilds.
What I discovered    The physics themselves are easy. Making them feel good, where the player feels in control, is hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Person View</title>
      <link>/projects/second_person_view/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/second_person_view/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve seen first person games. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen third person games. But what about second person games?
I sought to answer this universal, ubiquitious, and oft asked question the only way I knew how: through annoyance, frustration, and Unity3D.
The premise quickly became apparent, albeit quite simple. You control the view of another person, while they control yours. You have a body you can move around, but your eyes (and the control of them) belong to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevator Simulator</title>
      <link>/projects/elevator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/elevator/</guid>
      <description>I have always loved elevator programming, and the small details and differences between the programming in different elevators. While seemingly identical, a trained eye can notice small differences in how elevators operate.
But the details are rarely as simple or straightforward as they might seem. When considering the system, it becomes easy to become overwhelmed with what we optimize for: shorter ride times, shorter wait times, weight/capacity, wear on elevator (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mannyverse: A 3D Web3gl Game</title>
      <link>/projects/mannyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mannyverse/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: At one point I was intrigued by the idea of using verifiably scarce digital assets as primitives in video games. However revealed incentives of both studios and players signal the near impossibility of this. CS:GO will never use NFTs for game skins, because they have no financial incentive to do so, and the NFT ecosystem as a whole quickly (maybe immediately) became basterdized by get rich quick schemes, ignoring technological curiosities for sole monetary gain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threekly 2: It Continues...</title>
      <link>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.17.21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.17.21/</guid>
      <description>The threeklies continue&amp;hellip;
1. A podcast I&amp;rsquo;ve been binging    Anthony Pomliano    This video does a great job explaining it, but in short, it deals with Set Theory. Imagine a set that contains all sets that do not contain itself. Does this set contain itself? The rules of the set says it both should, and should not&amp;hellip;
2. A project I&amp;rsquo;ve come to love    Loot Project    Loot Project is the brain child of Dom Hoffman, the creator of the once loved Vine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threekly 1: The first Threekly!</title>
      <link>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.10.21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.10.21/</guid>
      <description>And thus begins my first weekly. A major point of this is exercise is to keep engaged and up to date with both current events and current media. I often find myself wishing I had kept more up-to-date with certain happenings, and this is my chance to mitigate any of that in the future. With that being said, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in to this week&amp;rsquo;s Threekly:
1. A thought problem I&amp;rsquo;ve been consumed with:    Russell&amp;rsquo;s Paradox    This video does a great job explaining it, but in short, it deals with Set Theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying Blind, a heart-beat sensing game</title>
      <link>/projects/past_project_spotlight_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/past_project_spotlight_1/</guid>
      <description>Code
Design    Flying blind is an experimental VR game where controls are confided to the heart. Put simply, raise your heartrate to go up, lower your heart rate to go down.
The purpose of this prototype was to incorporate controls that extended beyond the traditional human-computer interaction in game design.
To achieve this, I chose to use off-the-shelf hardware to track a user&amp;rsquo;s heartbeat, which in turn controls the ship they are on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VR Time Machine</title>
      <link>/projects/vr_time_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/vr_time_machine/</guid>
      <description>The VR Time Machine is a tool I built to organize and visualize my &amp;ldquo;memories&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Spencer Obsitnik (born Speezy F Baby, November 17, 1995) is an Oscar nominated child of four. After inventing Facebook and winning &amp;ldquo;Least Likely to Hyperbolize&amp;rdquo; in a grade school he did not attend, he rode 1000 miles on camelback to diffuse forgotten landmines. An Ashkenazi Jew by trade, and an Olympic surfer by birthright, he now lays dormant on his vast collections of beanie babies, oxford commas, and Cheerio&amp;rsquo;s Year 2000 pennies, where he wishes to be disturbed only by the Obamas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventor of Facebook</title>
      <link>/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facebook/</guid>
      <description>Spencer Obsitnik invented Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2birds1stone</title>
      <link>/projects/2birds1stone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2birds1stone/</guid>
      <description>2 Birds 1 Stone is the first game I ever built.
I was intrigued with VR, at the time a relatively new consumer technology. The idea that your body itself could be the controller, that physical actions you took could be accurately implemented in a game world, stood out to me.
So I started prototyping simple real world actions in the game. The simplest, and most rewarding action, was throwing. Something humans have always done, and now can do virtually as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
