<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spencerobsitnik</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on spencerobsitnik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mannyverse Puzzle</title>
      <link>/projects/mannyverse_puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mannyverse_puzzle/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll write it proper later&amp;hellip;
🥳🥳🥳 huge congrats to @spicedreams_ for finding the private key! Surprised it only took ~36 hours, will need to make the next one harder 😈 this nft gives free and early access to all my future projects! https://t.co/Ep5Djldl73
&amp;mdash; Spencer Obsitnik.Ξth (@spencerobsitnik) October 15, 2021  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mannyverse: A 3D Web3gl Game</title>
      <link>/projects/mannyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mannyverse/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Mannyverse.https://kintisbo.itch.io/mannyverse
The Mannyverse is a custom world I built for a popular 3D NFT called Mannys.game.
Mannys.game: An IntroManny is a person. Manny is also a collection of non-fungible digital clones of Manny.
The original NFT Manny created was released as a psycological game. He used a 3d body scan of himself as the token, modifying a select number to have a special characterstic (Zombie Manny, Inverted Manny, Silver Manny, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threekly 2: It Continues...</title>
      <link>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.17.21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.17.21/</guid>
      <description>The threeklies continue&amp;hellip;
1. A podcast I&amp;rsquo;ve been bingingAnthony PomlianoThis video does a great job explaining it, but in short, it deals with Set Theory. Imagine a set that contains all sets that do not contain itself. Does this set contain itself? The rules of the set says it both should, and should not&amp;hellip;
2. A project I&amp;rsquo;ve come to loveLoot ProjectLoot Project is the brain child of Dom Hoffman, the creator of the once loved Vine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threekly 1: The first Threekly!</title>
      <link>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.10.21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/threekly/threekly_fri_9.10.21/</guid>
      <description>And thus begins my first weekly. A major point of this is exercise is to keep engaged and up to date with both current events and current media. I often find myself wishing I had kept more up-to-date with certain happenings, and this is my chance to mitigate any of that in the future. With that being said, let&amp;rsquo;s dive in to this week&amp;rsquo;s Threekly:
1. A thought problem I&amp;rsquo;ve been consumed with:Russell&amp;rsquo;s ParadoxThis video does a great job explaining it, but in short, it deals with Set Theory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Token vs. Many Token</title>
      <link>/projects/one_token_many_token/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/one_token_many_token/</guid>
      <description>Both One Token and Many Token are under development and will be released soon! Stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Takeaways From Learning Ethereum</title>
      <link>/posts/learningsolidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learningsolidity/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months, I have done a deep dive in to Solidity and Ethereum development. This has included some Web3, but the main focus has been on Solidity and ERC standards. Below is a short list of resources I used, as well as some brief takeaways.
Resources I UsedNader Dabit. I cannot stress enough how phenomenal that guy is at teaching.
Tutorials https://cryptozombies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Function of Supply: An ERC-20 Experiment in Minimum Transactable Value</title>
      <link>/projects/the_function_of_supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/the_function_of_supply/</guid>
      <description>An Experiment in the Supply of ERC-20 TokensThis is still a work in progress
AbstractThis &amp;ldquo;greypaper&amp;rdquo; serves to identify a little discussed issue. Popular tokens like Ethereum and Bitcoin, as they gain popularity, inch closer to a divisibility bomb in what I&amp;rsquo;ve dubbed &amp;ldquo;the Satoshi problem.&amp;rdquo; High market cap coins with limited supply and fixed divisibility will eventually experience a slowdown in the network when users are unable to micro-transact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>/posts/firstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/firstpost/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post. It is a test post. It is a good post. It is not a fence post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Project Spotlight #1: Flying Blind, a heart-beat sensing game</title>
      <link>/projects/past_project_spotlight_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/past_project_spotlight_1/</guid>
      <description>Code
DesignThe purpose of this prototype was to incorporate controls that extended beyond the traditional human-computer interaction in game design.
To achieve this, I chose to use off-the-shelf hardware to track a user&amp;rsquo;s heartbeat, which in turn controls the ship they are on.
SoftwareThe game polls the heart rate monitor at a rate of 3 hz. At game start, I &amp;ldquo;calibrate&amp;rdquo; the sensor by taking the heart rate and computing a moving average across a range of 30 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Spencer Obsitnik (born Speezy F Baby, November 17, 1995) is an Oscar nominated child of four. After inventing Facebook and winning &amp;ldquo;Least Likely to Hyperbolize&amp;rdquo; in a grade school he did not attend, he rode 1000 miles on camelback to diffuse forgotten landmines. An Ashkenazi Jew by trade, and an Olympic surfer by birthright, he now lays dormant on his vast collections of oxford commas, beanie babies, and Cheerio&amp;rsquo;s Year 2000 pennies, where he wishes to be disturbed only by the Obamas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventor of Facebook</title>
      <link>/facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facebook/</guid>
      <description>Spencer Obsitnik invented Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
